Finding aid to Isabel Lindsay Papers CA.MS.00351
Smith College Archives
Isabel Lindsay papers
1903-1907
Smith College Archives
Lindsay, Isabel, 1886-1975
CA.MS.00351
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
These papers contain personal correspondence, primarily between Isabel Lindsay and her family during her years at Smith College.
Biographical / Historical
Isabel Gray Lindsay was born on February 4, 1886, in Milwaukee, WI. Before Smith, she attended Milwaukee-Downer Seminary preparatory school. Lindsay attended Smith College from 1903 to 1907. She lived in Haven House, 112 Elm Street, and at 30 Green Street. She was active in extracurricular activities in her senior year. Lindsay was president of the Phi Kappa Psi Honor Society, a senior member of La Societe Francais, chair of the Religious Service Committee and chair of Students' Exchange in the Smith College Association for Catholic Women, a Junior Usher, an honorary member of the Biological Society, a senior member of A.O.H March, and a senior member of "G.O.O.". After graduating Smith, Lindsay married Henry Frederic Helmholz and moved to Rochester, Minnesota. She had three children: Lindsay, who later attended Cornell University, Henry F. Jr., an alum of Dartmouth College, and Margaret, Class of 1939. Lindsay passed away on November 29, 1975.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains outgoing correspondence from Isabel Lindsay from 1903-1907, as well as some letters from her father, George Ingles Lindsay. There are also two essays she wrote for an ethics class and a religion class at Smith. The folders correspond with the academic semester in which Lindsay sent her letters.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Isabel Lindsay papers were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Smith College - Alumni and alumnae - History - Sources
- Correspondence: Fall 1903, Oct 2 - Dec 13, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Spring 1904, Feb 3 - June 13, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Fall 1904, Sept 26 - Dec 15, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Spring 1905, Jan 6 - June 18, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Fall 1905, Oct 15 - Dec 17, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Spring 1906, Jan 2 - June 7, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: Fall 1906, Sept 23 - Dec 16, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: Spring 1907, Jan 7 - May 22, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- College essays, 1903-1907 (Box 1, Folder 10)